Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today Marco
we're trying to make some plans. We're
trying to go to a restaurant. Correct?
That's right we want to go to a restaurant
tonight but before we have to call
them to make sure that there is a space or
room available for us. Alright so we're
going to hear a conversation between a
person at a restaurant who
works there and a person who
would like to go to that
restaurant. Let's take a listen.
Bruno Bistro how may I help you? Yes
hello I would like to make a reservation
please. Certainly sir for which day
and time please? Tonight at 7. I'm sorry
sir but we are fully booked tonight
until 8. In that case 8 o'clock is fine.
Very well and how many people will
attend tonight? Four people. Lastly may I
please know what name I should
make the reservation under. Alright we're
back so let's take a look at language
takeaway. Language takeaway.
So first of Marco we didn't hear the word
restaurant in today's dialogue. We heard a
different noun. We heard this Bistro.
That's right the name of the restaurant is
actually Bruno Bistro. So this restaurant
the type of restaurant this is it's
actually a Bistro. That's right so Bruno
is a name like Marco or Catherine but
Bistro is actually a special kind of small
restaurant and I believe it comes from
France right? Right that's right. So it's
kind of small and intimate maybe some
candles and lots of wine but it's not
like a big restaurant it's very romantic.
Right right which usually I found it means
that it's more expensive for some reason
because it's a Bistro it's automatically
more expensive. I think maybe in America
it's more expensive. Who knows maybe in
France it's the cheap option but Bistro is
the kind of place we're at and we'd like
to go so it's probably a popular place.
We need to make a reservation. That's
right. So as you see there we have a
verb there to make. We want to make a
reservation. So let's let's take a look at
the noun a
reservation. Reservation.
Reservation. So this
word means to to ask the
restaurant to hold your seats. So you
say listen I would like to come to your
restaurant tonight. I don't want to
wait when I come so I will call in advance.
I'll call early and ask them to
save a table for us. That's right so
this is called making a reservation.
So it goes together you call to make a
reservation or you want to make a reservation.
That's right so the verb is to make.
So I could say for example hey Marco
can you please make a reservation for
dinner tonight. I'm afraid there might
not be any tables left if we wait. Okay
very good. Now we can use the verb
reserve as well right. That's right so
reservation is a noun. To reserve is a
verb so I can say hey Marco can you please
reserve a table for dinner tonight?
Okay so we can say to make a reservation
or reserve a table. But you have to
say reserve a table. You can't say I would
like to reserve please. Now you have
to reserve something. So if I'm going to a
concert, a music concert I can say I'd
like to reserve two seats for the concert.
But if I'm going to dinner obviously
we sit at a table. So I'm going to
reserve a table. All right. Now moving
on to another verb the waiter or the person
in charge there asked us how many people
will attend dinner tonight. So how many
people will attend? To attend. Okay this
is another verb. To attend means to to be
there or to come. That's right. So it's
actually a nicer way of saying to come.
Instead of him saying how many people
will come tonight. He says how many people
will attend. All right so that's a question
for the person making their reservation.
How many people total? Right.
But it's like you say very polite.
You could say hey Marco how many people
do you think will attend your birthday
party next week? That's right. So I can
say well maybe ten people will attend.
Ten people will attend. So attend quite
a simple verb but just remember that it
means to come or to be present at. All
right great. So let's take a look at our
dialogue again. And then we'll be
back in a bit with fluency builder Bruno
Beast drove. How may I help you? Yes hello.
I would like to make a reservation
please. Certainly serve for which day
and time please. Tonight at seven. I'm
sorry sir but we are fully booked tonight
until eight. In that case eight o'clock
is fine. Very well and how many people will
attend tonight? Four people. Lastly may
I please know what name I should
make the reservation under? All right we've
picked up three phrases for you.
Let's take a look at those now on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. All right
so the first phrase we have on fluency
builder is actually a phrase you don't
want to hear when you're trying to make
a reservation. The person at the restaurant
the Beastrow said I'm sorry we're
fully booked until eight. That's right
so a place that is fully booked or maybe
a flight that's fully booked means
that it's completely full. There are no
available seats or available spots or
anything. All the tables have been reserved.
All right so this means that we have
to change either the day or the time.
That's right. It's fully booked but
the nice thing is that after eight o'clock
is not fully booked. There are free tables
after eight. That's right so he actually
went on to say of an interesting phrase
to start that sentence. He said in that
case eight o'clock is fine. In that case
so in that case is a great phrase to use
when you're having a conversation
with someone or a negotiation because it's
something that we say when the situation
okay like reserving a table is not
exactly the way we hoped it would be.
So with today's dialogue we wanted to
book a table at seven o'clock.
There was no table so in that case in that
situation because it changed from what
we thought we had to book a table at eight
instead. That's right so it's usually
a response to information that was
given to you right so they say oh I'm
sorry there are no tickets available for
the zoo today only for tomorrow. In
that case why don't we go tomorrow? That's
right. So I wanted to go today but the
situation changed or there's a problem in
that case let's change our plans.
That's right and lastly the waiter asked
may I please know what name I should
make the reservation under. What name I
should make the reservation under.
All right now to make a reservation we
already learned this phrase means to
reserve a table. Now to make a reservation
under a person's name this is quite
different right. This means that we're
going to save a table reserve a table
but we have to provide a name. Right so if
we say okay one table reserved for four
we don't know who. Right so this is the
name that you will give the waiter
when you arrive at the restaurant. That's
right so that is your table basically
and that's your reservation so if you go
to the restaurant you say hello I have
a reservation under the name of mark.
That's right I have a reservation
under the name mark or I have a
reservation for mark at eight o'clock.
Now when they ask the question they're
going to say what name should we make
the reservation under. That's because so
just think about it as when they make
the reservation they have this big book.
They write your name and underneath
they write the time. What name should we
make the reservation under. That's
right okay so we've taken a look at a lot
of vocab and some really good phrases so
let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
Bruno Beastrow how may I help you? Yes
hello I would like to make a reservation
please. Certainly serve for which day
and time please. Tonight at seven. I'm
sorry sir but we are fully booked tonight
until eight. In that case eight o'clock
is fine. Very well and how many
people will attend tonight? Four people.
Lastly may please know what name
I should make the reservation under.
Language take care. All right we're
back so making a reservation now this is
fairly easy. This is basically what
you're going to experience if you call it
any restaurant to make a reservation right.
That's right and it's really
important to know how to respond
because I know in other languages sometimes
you reserve seats instead of tables.
Right and so in English we reserve or we
book a table. Now sometimes you will
call a place and you'll say well I'd like
to make a reservation and they will
say I'm sorry we don't accept reservations.
Yes this is actually a very
frustrating situation especially if a
restaurant or beastrow is very popular.
Right because if they don't accept
reservations we don't make reservations
that means that you have to go to the
restaurant and maybe wait in line for
a table. That's right that's called I think
first come first served. That's right
first come first serve so that means that
the first people to arrive at the restaurant
are the first people to get a table.
So it's smart to arrive early. That's
right so that's what happens now
there there are certain restaurants
where you can't make a reservations or
different we took a look at a beastrow.
There's another one like for example
very popular in the U.S. a diner.
A diner now this is not a place you need to
make a reservation for. A normally
a diner is a very casual place to eat.
You can go at nine o'clock in the morning
for breakfast it's not very fancy at all.
Right and it's open I think 24 hours
usually. Many of them are open 24 hours and
that's why I say it's not a place you
need to worry about a reservation
because they're usually popular at
certain times but like seven o'clock for
breakfast or you know right 12 o'clock
for lunch but you can usually get a table.
Right all right so if you guys have
any questions or any other doubts you
can find us at EnglishPod.com
and we'll see everyone there. Bye!
(upbeat music)